<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Duncan Plumbing Solutions</title>
	<atom:link href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com</link>
	<description>Plumbing Repair, Installation &#38; Service</description>
	<lastBuildDate>
	Thu, 20 Jun 2019 16:42:04 +0000	</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-icon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Duncan Plumbing Solutions</title>
	<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Can Flies Be a Sign of Household Plumbing Leaks?</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/household-plumbing-leaks/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/household-plumbing-leaks/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 16:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Leak location and repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Best Plumber Waxahachie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken water main]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clogged lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leak location]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Midlothian Plumber 76065]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[need a plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Leak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing leaks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Repair.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Oak Plumber 75154. Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sewer cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sewer problem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water main break]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7810</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Tale-Tell Signs of a Plumbing Leak Knowing These Clues Can Prevent Major Household Plumbing Leak or Sewer Problem. Drain flies are also known as the drain moth fly is actually a small, dark winged gnat. Like the mosquito, these inspects breed in standing water. This means your home drain can be the perfect breeding ground [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/household-plumbing-leaks/">Can Flies Be a Sign of Household Plumbing Leaks?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Tale-Tell Signs of a Plumbing Leak</h1>
<p>Knowing These Clues Can Prevent Major Household Plumbing Leak or Sewer Problem. Drain flies are also known as the drain moth fly is actually a small, dark winged gnat. Like the mosquito, these inspects breed in standing water. This means your home drain can be the perfect breeding ground for this annoying little bugger. Like the pesky fruit fly, you may notice them when you return from vacation or being away for the weekend. This is because the water in your sink or drain sits stagnant for a time without water being run or moving through the pipe systems. These usually disappear when things are back to normal and water is run through the pipes and sewer systems are moving again.</p>
<h2>Are the Flies a Sign of Breeding in Your Home&#8217;s Plumbing System?</h2>
<figure id="attachment_7812" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7812" style="width: 273px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/household-plumbing-leaks/drain-flies/" rel="attachment wp-att-7812"><img class="size-full wp-image-7812" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/drain-flies.jpg" alt="Plumbing Leak, Sewer Back Up Sewer " width="273" height="183" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7812" class="wp-caption-text">Flies Are A Sign of A Plumbing Leak, Back Up or Sewer Issues</figcaption></figure>
<p>If you haven’t been away and notice flies this could be a sign of a household plumbing leak. If you notice flies in your home but haven’t been away first you want to see if they are adult or juvenile flies. If they are adult flies, it could be they came from the outside in and have just found their way inside. If you see a number of juvenile flies, chances are they are inside and breeding indoors—perhaps in your home’s plumbing and drain system! Remember how quickly flies multiply? I think every high school in America had the fruit fly experiment gone wrong when the school becomes infested with fruit flies, lol!Flies are usually just annoying but they can help you  identify plumbing problems</p>
<h2>The fly can be the key to early detection of a sewer problem!</h2>
<p>Like the crime scene detective, these guys can actually help you find out that you actually have hidden leaks within the walls of your home. You may have other leaks inside your home. These flies will breed in any moist area that they can find. So if you are facing a drain fly infestation that you cannot figure it out, you may want to look deeper for the cause. The problem could be from a leaking pipe or drain under the sink or even a leaking pipe inside of your walls.</p>
<h3>A Little Plumbing Problem Can Become a Big Problem Fast!</h3>
<p>Once you realize you have a problem, call a plumber like <a href="http://www.duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> who will locate and identify the plumbing problem that is causing the drain flies. Knowing These Clues Can Prevent Major Household Plumbing Leak or Sewer Problem. From there, <a href="http://www.duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> will make any needed repairs and rid you of these pests once and for all. Leaky pipes that are left to leak over periods of time will cause major problems to your home so you can thank these little detectives for helping you identify the problem before the leak has caused the woodwork in your home to rot or make its way through your ceiling or floor. A slow leaking pipe can quickly turn into a pipe that will flood your entire home and belongings. This is worse-case scenario and maybe these little ‘pests’ can save you the headache and hassle with the help of solution providers like <a href="http://www.duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/household-plumbing-leaks/">Can Flies Be a Sign of Household Plumbing Leaks?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/household-plumbing-leaks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>THOUSANDS OF TEXAS PLUMBERS RALLY AT THE STATE CAPITOL</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 18:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affordable plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drain clean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drain cleaner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drain cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duncan Plumbing Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duncan Plumbing Solutions In Waxahachie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[licensed plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[need a plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumber in waxahachie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing journeyman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Repair.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanitary sewer system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7793</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week thousands of Texas Plumbers converged on the State Capitol. The board that licenses plumbers in Texas was not renewed earlier when lawmakers closed the session failing to pass a bill to renew the current board the TSBPE – Texas State Board of Plumbing Examiners, leaving thousands of Texas Master Plumbers, Journeymen and professional [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/">THOUSANDS OF TEXAS PLUMBERS RALLY AT THE STATE CAPITOL</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_7795" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7795" style="width: 825px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/img_6082/" rel="attachment wp-att-7795"><img class=" wp-image-7795" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6082.jpg" alt="Plumber Rally in Austin" width="825" height="619" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6082.jpg 4032w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6082-300x225.jpg 300w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6082-768x576.jpg 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6082-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 825px) 100vw, 825px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7795" class="wp-caption-text">Plumbers Converge on State Capitol in Austin</figcaption></figure>
<p>Last week thousands of Texas Plumbers converged on the State Capitol. The <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">board that licenses plumbers</a> in Texas was not renewed earlier when lawmakers closed the session failing to pass a bill to renew the current board the <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE – Texas State Board of Plumbing Examiners</a>, leaving thousands of Texas Master Plumbers, Journeymen and professional Drain Cleaners in limbo. At the last minute, Governor Gregg Abbott issued an executive order to keep it going.  This is good news for plumbers and the general public but it’s really a temporary fix. <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/about/">Mike Duncan</a> with Duncan Plumbing Solutions in Waxahachie states, “Governor Abbott issued pretty much a delay from the plumbing board, instead of fixing the problem by calling a special session.”</p>
<p>Some lawmakers in the house felt it was more appropriate for plumbing to be managed by the <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">Texas Department of Licensing and Regulation (TDLR).</a> I couldn’t help but notice the <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">TDLR</a> stamp on the elevator I was on while in Austin for the rally. Hummmmm, the same agency that regulates the safety of every elevator in Texas is going to also regulate the entire plumbing industry?</p>
<p>The TDLR provides oversight for a broad range of occupations, businesses, facilities, and equipment. They oversee everything from Barbeque to Behavior Analysis; from laser hair removal to licensed dog breeders. You can read more about TDLR on their website here: <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/</a>about.htm</p>
<p>Formed in 1947, the mission of the <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">Texas State Board of Plumbing Examiners (TSBPE)</a> is to protect Texas citizens against the health and safety hazards that can result from improperly installed plumbing, gas, and medical gas systems.  Under the current system, it takes 8 years for a Master Plumber to obtain his accreditation.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> administers and enforces Chapter 1301 of the Texas Occupations Code (Plumbing License Law). The agency’s main functions can be separated into four categories: examination, licensing, enforcement, and administration.  The TSBPEs sole business is regarding the requirements of the Plumbing License Law and rules adopted by the Board, and the dangerous conditions that can arise from improperly installed plumbing. You can read more about the TSBPE here: <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">https://tsbpe.texas.gov/</a></p>
<h1>CHANGE IS NEEDED</h1>
<figure id="attachment_7796" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7796" style="width: 3024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/img_6072/" rel="attachment wp-att-7796"><img class="wp-image-7796 size-full" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6072-e1560967654322.jpg" alt="Plumbing " width="3024" height="4032" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6072-e1560967654322.jpg 3024w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6072-e1560967654322-225x300.jpg 225w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6072-e1560967654322-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 3024px) 100vw, 3024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7796" class="wp-caption-text">Plumbers Marching on Texas Capitol in Austin</figcaption></figure>
<p>A report to the Sunset Commission recommended changes to the current system to speed up the process of obtaining various certifications. People are waiting months just to sit for an exam. Some call the current system “outdated” and including much “unnecessary paper exams and practical exams”.  The agency is underfunded. It seems lawmakers thought if the<a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/"> TSBPE</a> can’t get it right, we’ll appropriate another agency that will. But is this the answer?</p>
<h1>SHOW ME THE MONEY!</h1>
<figure id="attachment_7797" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7797" style="width: 3024px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/img_6076/" rel="attachment wp-att-7797"><img class="wp-image-7797 size-full" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6076-e1560967780774.jpg" alt="Change is Inevitable" width="3024" height="4032" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6076-e1560967780774.jpg 3024w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6076-e1560967780774-225x300.jpg 225w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6076-e1560967780774-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 3024px) 100vw, 3024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7797" class="wp-caption-text">Change is Inevitable</figcaption></figure>
<p>What will all this ultimately mean for affordable plumbing? The bill would delay the transfer of plumbing regulation to <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">TDLR</a> until no later than September 1, 2020 and this analysis assumes the regulatory operation costs will continue at <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> until that date. Abolishing <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> would result in General Revenue of $2,893,085 in fiscal year 2021, $2,656,177 in fiscal year 2022, and $2,154,302 per fiscal year thereafter. These amounts include one-time costs for computer equipment, rent, and furniture for the new FTEs at <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">TDLR</a>, vehicle fleet maintenance, salaries and benefits for the 28.0 full-time equivalent (FTE) positions to operate the plumbing program at <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">TDLR</a>, and technology costs.</p>
<p>According to Sunset staff analysis, the elimination of the drain cleaner, drain cleaner-restricted, and residential utilities install registrations would result in a revenue loss of approximately $41,800 per fiscal year to the General Revenue Fund—not much of a loss. Replacing the master plumber designation with a plumbing contractor license could result in an increase of revenue as additional persons would be eligible to obtain licensure – i.e. anyone could be a plumber.  In this case, they say ‘the overall effect on revenue cannot be determined’. This bill would open up licensure to anyone tradesman or handy man and gain more revenue in the short term. Fees related to reciprocity and temporary licenses, endorsements, and certificates of registration would be set by <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">TDLR</a> and the effect on revenue cannot be determined.</p>
<p>According to Sunset staff analysis of contracts currently held by the plumbing board, certain contracts established by and for the plumbing board would no longer be required at <a href="https://www.tdlr.texas.gov/">TDLR</a>. This is alarming, says <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/about/">Erica Duncan of Duncan Plumbing Solutions in Waxahachie.</a> What does this mean for the health and general safety of plumbing systems like clean water and sanitary sewer systems?</p>
<figure id="attachment_7798" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7798" style="width: 3024px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/img_6070/" rel="attachment wp-att-7798"><img class="wp-image-7798 size-full" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6070-e1560967858429.jpg" alt="Mike Duncan, Master Plumber at Duncan Plumbing Solutions" width="3024" height="4032" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6070-e1560967858429.jpg 3024w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6070-e1560967858429-225x300.jpg 225w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6070-e1560967858429-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 3024px) 100vw, 3024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7798" class="wp-caption-text">Mike Duncan, Master Plumber at Duncan Plumbing Solutions</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> currently performs criminal background checks on applicants; however, these background checks do not meet the fingerprint and FBI requirements of the bill.  So the <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> adds fingerprint and background checks? How easy is that? The proposed bill would require applicants and licensees to pay for the cost of the fingerprint background checks through the Department of Public Safety&#8217;s (DPS). This would generate an additional nearly 1.5M in the first year and 1,712,995 in the year 2021. Of this amount, $682,166 would be remitted to the FBI and $1,030,829 would be retained by DPS to offset costs associated with providing background checks.</p>
<p>This bill would amend Chapter 1301 of the Occupations Code to implement Sunset Commission recommendations regarding the <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> and transfer the regulation of plumbers to the Texas Department of Licensing and Regulation (TDLR) no later than September 1, 2020. The bill would abolish <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> and establish the Texas Plumbing Advisory Board to provide recommendations to TDLR regarding the administration of this chapter. The bill would eliminate the drain cleaner, drain cleaner-restricted and residential utilities installer registration and would eliminate the master plumber designation and replace it with a plumbing contractor license.  Change is needed but this would be like the pendulum swinging grossly in the opposite direction,  says Erica Duncan of Duncan Plumbing Solutions.</p>
<h1>CHANGE IS COMING</h1>
<figure id="attachment_7799" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7799" style="width: 3024px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/img_6079/" rel="attachment wp-att-7799"><img class="wp-image-7799 size-full" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6079-e1560967986838.jpg" alt="Plumbers " width="3024" height="4032" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6079-e1560967986838.jpg 3024w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6079-e1560967986838-225x300.jpg 225w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/IMG_6079-e1560967986838-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 3024px) 100vw, 3024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7799" class="wp-caption-text">Change Sure to Come</figcaption></figure>
<p>Romans 8:28 God works all for the good for those called according to His purpose. Maybe this short of shake up is needed to bring awareness to the many areas needing improvement.  It remains to be seen how this will all shake out but one thing we want to see is the pendulum will settle on some middle ground that incorporates some of the suggested changes but keeping the current board in place while improving the current systems, long wait times to sit for the exam, paper exams, funding, and other antiquated systems which are in place currently with the <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE.</a> We are hoping the pendulum settles on some middle ground where this industry is protected and that the swing settles on a change for the better. Sometimes it takes a shake-up for real, positive change to take place. We’re hoping and praying that is exactly what happens to the <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/">THOUSANDS OF TEXAS PLUMBERS RALLY AT THE STATE CAPITOL</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/thousands-of-texas-plumbers-rally-at-the-state-capitol/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHAT DOES TEXAS PLUMBING BOARD DEREGULATION MEAN FOR YOU?</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 20:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Plumbing in the News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[75104 plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affordable plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercial plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duncan Plumbing Solutions In Waxahachie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ennis repipe 75119]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I need a plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[licensed plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[need a plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumber near me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Oak Plumber 75154]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repipe house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[replace galvanized pipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[replace old pipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water main break]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waxahachie install water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7782</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Just about this same time last June, more than 1M (Million) gallons of raw sewage came spilling into North Central Texas waterways north of Waxahachie in Plano when a waste-water pipe broke near Toyota of Plano.  Texans were shocked as the raw sewage headed for White Rock Lake in Dallas. In March 2019, The Garland [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/">WHAT DOES TEXAS PLUMBING BOARD DEREGULATION MEAN FOR YOU?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just about this same time last June, more than 1M (Million) gallons of raw sewage came spilling into North Central Texas waterways north of Waxahachie in Plano when a waste-water pipe broke near Toyota of Plano.  Texans were shocked as the raw sewage headed for White Rock Lake in Dallas. In March 2019, The Garland Health Department was busy monitoring water quality in Spring Creek after a sanitary <em>sewer</em> overflowed, dumping thousands of gallons of <em>raw sewage</em> into the waterway.  Just a short three days ago, after explosion killed Dallas 12-year-old, Texas to remove most dangerous natural gas pipes by 2021. We all remember the explosion that rocked homes near Waxahachie when natural gas exploded. We’ve had too many natural gas explosions in recent months, explains Mike Duncan, Master Plumber at <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> in Waxahachie. This is far bigger than an unlicensed handy-man fixing a leak under your sink. These are just a couple of examples of how plumbers maintain health and safety for the general population.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7790" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7790" style="width: 508px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/wrench-general-for-plumbing/" rel="attachment wp-att-7790"><img class="size-full wp-image-7790" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Wrench-general-for-plumbing.jpg" alt="History of Plumbing in Waxahachie" width="508" height="330" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Wrench-general-for-plumbing.jpg 508w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Wrench-general-for-plumbing-300x195.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 508px) 100vw, 508px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7790" class="wp-caption-text">PLUMBING HISTORY</figcaption></figure>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2>A LITTLE HISTORY ON PLUMBING</h2>
<p>Plumbing is among one of the oldest professions in history. In ancient Mesopotamia, civilizations sprouted along water ways and builders emerged and developed their roles among society. Aside from Farmer, Musician, Artist, Story-Teller, Clothier, Hunter, Butcher and Toolmaker, Plumbing has been a staple job and always will because it deals with the most basic human needs.  When you think of a civilized society, you think of running water. Harmful microorganisms like E. Coli, Campylobacter, Hepatitis, Giardia, Salmonella, Legionella and cryptosporidium can all be transmitted by unclean water. The word &#8220;plumber&#8221; dates from the Roman Empire. The Latin for lead is plumbum. Roman roofs used lead in conduits and drain pipes and some were also covered with lead, lead was also used for piping and for making baths. In medieval times anyone who worked with lead was referred to as a plumber. A person with expertise in working with lead was first known as a Plumbarius which was later shortened to plumber. In recent days, Texas lawmakers responsible for regulating this vitally important industry came under fire.</p>
<h2>IS THE TSBPE UNRAVELING?</h2>
<p><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/tsbpe-capture/" rel="attachment wp-att-7783"><img class="alignleft wp-image-7783 size-full" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/TSBPE-capture.jpg" alt="TSBPE is the Texas Plumbing Governing Board" width="616" height="170" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/TSBPE-capture.jpg 616w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/TSBPE-capture-300x83.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 616px) 100vw, 616px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Texas lawmakers ended their session last week without passing legislation that would keep the Texas State Board of Plumbing Examiners intact. The <a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">TSBPE</a> oversees licenses of approximately 60,000 plumbers in Texas. Now the state of Texas’ plumbing code and state licenses are set to expire 1 September.  Days later, Governor Greg Abbott reassured Texans saying he can keep plumbing board alive without special session.  “We’ve got this,&#8221; Governor Abbott tells worried plumbers, citizens and consumers.  Abbott tweeted, &#8220;The Legislature has given the Governor many tools in my toolbox to extend the State Board of Plumbing Examiners for two years without needing to call a special session. We will let you know very soon. Don’t worry.&#8221;</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear how Abbott would rescue the board, a state agency that licenses plumbers and regulates the industry. The board is set to wind down and cease existing in 2020 after state lawmakers recently failed to pass legislation that would have extended the agency&#8217;s life. Lawmakers also wiped out the part of the state code that gives Texas the authority to regulate the profession in the first place.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7784" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7784" style="width: 569px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/governor-greg-abbott/" rel="attachment wp-att-7784"><img class="wp-image-7784" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Governor-Greg-Abbott.jpg" alt="Greg Abbott reassures Texas Plumbers " width="569" height="368" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Governor-Greg-Abbott.jpg 766w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Governor-Greg-Abbott-300x194.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 569px) 100vw, 569px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7784" class="wp-caption-text">Texas Governor Greg Abbott</figcaption></figure>
<h1></h1>
<h1></h1>
<h1></h1>
<h1></h1>
<h1></h1>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2>WHAT SORT OF EDUCATION AND TRAINING ARE REQUIRED?</h2>
<p>Plumbers are required to have hours of education, documented on the job training and apprenticeship work. In Texas, there are four professional levels for a plumber:</p>
<p>1) Plumber’s Apprentice (Must be registered, sponsored by an employer)</p>
<p>2) Tradesman Plumber-4000 Hours or about 2 years of documented experience documented on Certified Employer Verification forms, testing and license required.  A Tradesman Plumber must have a current Texas Plumber’s Apprentice registration or have a valid Journeyman or Master Plumber license from another state and at least 4,000 hours of experience working at the trade under the general supervision of a Master Plumber.  A Tradesman must have completed 24 hours of Board approved classroom training and must pass the License exam.  It is a three part exam, one written and two hands-on.</p>
<p>3) Journeyman Plumber &#8211; 8000 Hours or about 4 years of documented experience, testing and license required.  A Journeyman Plumber must have plumber experience documented on Certified Employer Verification forms. He must have a current Texas Plumber’s Apprentice registration, a current Texas Tradesman Plumber-Limited license, or a valid Journeyman or Master Plumber license from another state. He must have completed 48 hours of Board approved classroom training from a certified and approved training facility and have passed license and examination.</p>
<p>Texas Master Plumber License Requirements</p>
<p>The Texas state requires you must be currently licensed as a Journeyman Plumber in Texas or another state with at least 8,000 or 4 years of documented experience and have held the Journeyman Plumber license for at least one (1) year or have successfully completed a training program approved by the United States Department of Labor Office of Apprenticeship, or four (4) years, or  no minimum / not applicable if you hold a current Master Plumber license in another state with at least 8,000 hours working at the trade.</p>
<p>The Master Plumber must also pass the License exam.</p>
<h2>WHAT CAN I EXPECT FROM DUNCAN PLUMBING SOLUTIONS?</h2>
<p><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/md-ipad-and-phone-474/" rel="attachment wp-att-7785"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-7785" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/MD-Ipad-and-phone-474.jpg" alt="" width="1913" height="1832" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/MD-Ipad-and-phone-474.jpg 1913w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/MD-Ipad-and-phone-474-300x287.jpg 300w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/MD-Ipad-and-phone-474-768x735.jpg 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/MD-Ipad-and-phone-474-1024x981.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1913px) 100vw, 1913px" /></a></p>
<p>If you are looking for reliable, experienced technicians, look no further than Duncan Plumbing Solutions, LLC. At <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>, we pride ourselves on our dedication to our customers and precision attention to detail. <strong>Our Plumbers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Passed a criminal background check</li>
<li>May not be an offender of any kind or have blemishes on their record</li>
<li>Are fully licensed and insured</li>
<li>Have passed all required licensing exams</li>
<li>Are fully endorsed by the Texas State Board of Plumbing Examiners (<a href="https://tsbpe.texas.gov/">https://tsbpe.texas.gov/</a>)</li>
<li>Can provide proof of commercial liability insurance</li>
<li>Consistently attend continuing education courses to further knowledge</li>
</ul>
<p>Don’t trust your home or business to just anyone. With <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>, you have a guarantee our plumbers have fulfilled each and every one of the above requirements. Trust the plumbing experts at <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> to install or repair you plumbing and ensure it is up to code. Check out some of our reviews.</p>
<h2>WHAT ABOUT RESPONSIBLE MASTER PLUMBER MICHAEL DUNCAN?</h2>
<figure id="attachment_7522" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7522" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/about/hotwater_right/" rel="attachment wp-att-7522"><img class="size-full wp-image-7522" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/hotwater_right.jpg" alt="Water Heater Installation" width="600" height="450" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/hotwater_right.jpg 600w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/hotwater_right-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7522" class="wp-caption-text">Water Heater Installation</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> proudly serves under the direction of Master Plumber Mike Duncan who has years of experience in the Plumbing industry. He not only has many years of expert plumbing training but has undergone rigorous testing proving understanding and abilities to demonstrate proper installation of commercial and residential plumbing systems. He also attends hours of yearly continuing education.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The examination relates to work performed and decisions made on the job and consists of:</p>
<ul>
<li>210 written multiple choice questions; including</li>
<li>60 questions based on Plumbing Codes;</li>
<li>25 questions based on the Plumbing Codes, specific to water heater installation;</li>
<li>25 questions on the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) Code Federal Regulations;</li>
<li>25 questions on the Texas Accessibility Standards (TAS), as they apply to plumbing fixture installations;</li>
<li>25 questions on Liquefied Petroleum Gas piping installation;</li>
<li>25 questions on Plumbing Related Mathematics; and</li>
<li>25 questions on the Plumbing License Law and Board Rules;</li>
<li>1 Fuel Gas Pipe Sizing chart;</li>
<li>1 Water Pipe Sizing chart;</li>
<li>1 Gas Fueled Appliance Vent Sizing chart;</li>
<li>1 Drainage System Pipe Sizing chart; and</li>
<li>1 Design of a three story sanitary drainage and vent system for sixteen (16) plumbing fixtures.</li>
</ul>
<p>Contact information:</p>
<p>Texas State Board of Plumbing Examiners</p>
<p>P.O. Box 4200</p>
<p>Austin, TX  78765</p>
<p>512-936-5200</p>
<p>TSBPE websi</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/">WHAT DOES TEXAS PLUMBING BOARD DEREGULATION MEAN FOR YOU?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/what-does-texas-plumbing-board-deregulation-mean-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Looking For A Plumber to Install, Service or Repair Gas Lines?</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 14:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gas Lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[and odors from gas or electric water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Certified gas line replace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy star appliance installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expert Gas Line Installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install gas line Desoto Plumber 75115]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[licensed gas plumbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mansfield Plumber 76063 install gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master plumber gas line repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing gas certified]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing gas lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Oak Plumber 75154 install gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas Gas Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waxahachie install gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165 install gas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7773</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Do Plumbers Deal With Gas? When you think of plumbing, chances are you’re thinking of things like fix a clogged toilet, repairing a faucet or sink, pipes that carry water and sewage, as well as do installation and repair jobs for faucets, sinks, garbage disposals, sewer lines, etc. You’re probably thinking of all the parts [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/">Are You Looking For A Plumber to Install, Service or Repair Gas Lines?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Do Plumbers Deal With Gas?</h1>
<p>When you think of plumbing, chances are you’re thinking of things like fix a clogged toilet, repairing a faucet or sink, pipes that carry water and sewage, as well as do installation and repair jobs for faucets, sinks, garbage disposals, sewer lines, etc. You’re probably thinking of all the parts of the freshwater and wastewater system of a home or commercial building.</p>
<h2>Can a Plumber Run a Gas Line?</h2>
<figure id="attachment_7776" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7776" style="width: 287px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/duncan-long-logo-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-7776"><img class="size-full wp-image-7776" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Duncan-Long-logo-1.jpg" alt="Waxahachie Gas Line Installation Service Repair" width="287" height="52" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7776" class="wp-caption-text">Duncan Plumbing Solutions is Fully Licensed to Handle Gas Installation, Service &amp; Repair</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Natural and propane gas pipes are an important part of the services some professional plumbers like <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#gas-lines">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> offer. Many plumbers are NOT certified in this area. However, if you are looking for a plumber to install or work with alternative fuels such as liquid propane, natural gas or medical gas in Waxahachie, Ellis County or the Dallas or Ft. Worth metroplex, look no further than <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#gas-lines">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>. We can install, service or repair the gas piping for your home or business. We’re a full-service plumbing company that can handle any gas job, big or small from LPG, Propane, Butane, and Natural Gas.</p>
<h2>You Must Hire a Plumber with Special Gas Certification</h2>
<figure id="attachment_7470" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7470" style="width: 248px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/picture1-2/"><img class="size-full wp-image-7470" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Picture1-1.png" alt="Duncan Plumbing Gas Installation " width="248" height="310" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Picture1-1.png 248w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Picture1-1-240x300.png 240w" sizes="(max-width: 248px) 100vw, 248px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7470" class="wp-caption-text">Duncan Plumbing is Certified by Texas RRC to work with Specialty Gas</figcaption></figure>
<p>It’s illegal for just any plumber to work on a pipe or appliance connected to a gas main unless they have a special license to do so. Not only are professional gas plumbers the only people with the skill to do the job, they are the only people who are allowed to do the job. There’s good reason for this limitation! Leaking gas lines are tremendous health hazards. Gas explosions have been in the news in Ellis County and all around Waxahachie. Make sure you stay safe and see that properly licensed professional plumbers such as <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#gas-lines">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> handle all your gas piping services.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Who Regulates and Licenses Plumbers to Install and Repair Gas Lines in Texas?</h2>
<figure id="attachment_7775" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7775" style="width: 728px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/railroad-commission/" rel="attachment wp-att-7775"><img class="size-full wp-image-7775" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Railroad-Commission.jpg" alt="Plumbing gas regulations " width="728" height="172" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Railroad-Commission.jpg 728w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Railroad-Commission-300x71.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7775" class="wp-caption-text">Texas RRC Regulates Plumbing regarding Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG, Propane, Butane), Compressed Natural Gas (CNG), and Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG)</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Railroad Commission of Texas is the state agency responsible for regulating the safe storage, transportation and use of Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG, Propane, Butane), Compressed Natural Gas (CNG), and Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG), pursuant to the Texas Natural Resources Code (TNRC). The Commission has also adopted regulations for each fuel type under the Texas Administrative Code, Title 16, Chapters 9, 13, and 14, respectively. <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#gas-lines">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> is fully licensed with the The Railroad Commission of Texas to safely work with plumbing gas lines.</p>
<p>The Alternative Fuels Safety (AFS) department enforces both the state statutes and the Commission’s regulations on these fuels, by conducting safety evaluations of stationary facilities and mobile equipment, licensing companies engaged in alternative fuel activities, and providing training to individuals working in the alternative fuels industries.</p>
<h2>DUNCAN PLUMBING SPECIALLY CERTIFIED TO HANDLE Compressed Natural Gas &amp; Propane</h2>
<p>The Alternative Fuels Safety (AFS) department of the Railroad Commission of Texas is charged with adopting and enforcing regulations for the safe storage, transportation and use of gas, including Compressed Natural Gas (CNG) in the State of Texas. Plumbers like <a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#gas-lines">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a> are certified and licensed with the State of Texas through the Railroad Commission of Texas and are responsible for complying with state statutes, the Commission&#8217;s safety rules and adopted national and federal codes that are specific to each installation type.</p>
<p>Our gas plumbers do many repair jobs, but they’re also available to assist with new gas line installation. Gas is the #1 choice for chefs and the preferred method of cooking. It is also the best choice if you are going with a tankless water heater. There are many benefits to expanding use of natural gas. Talk to our plumbers to find out what we can do to put in more gas lines for your appliances.</p>
<p>For your home, you may be considering changing out an old electric clothes dryer for a gas-powered one—a much more powerful unit, and also less expensive to run. To have the new gas lines put in to run the laundry machine, you’ll also want our professionals to do the work.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7774" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7774" style="width: 4032px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/md-ipad-and-phone-1666/" rel="attachment wp-att-7774"><img class="size-full wp-image-7774" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MD-Ipad-and-phone-1666.jpg" alt="Plumbing Gas Appliances" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MD-Ipad-and-phone-1666.jpg 4032w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MD-Ipad-and-phone-1666-300x225.jpg 300w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MD-Ipad-and-phone-1666-768x576.jpg 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/MD-Ipad-and-phone-1666-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7774" class="wp-caption-text">Plumbing Gas Appliances</figcaption></figure>
<p>We encourage both homes and businesses to look into ways to increase their use of natural gas, which is a safe, clean-burning, inexpensive fuel that’s domestically produced and readily available.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/">Are You Looking For A Plumber to Install, Service or Repair Gas Lines?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/are-you-looking-for-a-plumber-to-install-service-or-repair-gas-lines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Texas Energy Star and Water-Efficient Products Sales Tax Holiday May 25, 26, 27 2019</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-energy-star-and-water-efficient-products-sales-tax-holiday-may-25-26-27-2019/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-energy-star-and-water-efficient-products-sales-tax-holiday-may-25-26-27-2019/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 14:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Appliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Green Plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appliance installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cedar Hill Plumber 75104]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Desoto Plumber 75115]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duncan Plumbing Solutions to install a water cut off]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duncanville Plumber 75116]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy star appliance installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ennis Plumber 75119]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mansfield Plumber 76063]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[need a plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumber fix leak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumber in ovilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Repair.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Oak Plumber 75154]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water heater installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7760</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>This Memorial Day Weekend, you can buy certain ENERGY STAR® energy-efficient products tax-free during the annual Texas ENERGY STAR Sales Tax Holiday. There is no limit on the number of qualifying items you can buy, and you do not need to give the seller an exemption certificate to buy items tax free. Qualifying Products You can buy, rent or lease only the following [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-energy-star-and-water-efficient-products-sales-tax-holiday-may-25-26-27-2019/">Texas Energy Star and Water-Efficient Products Sales Tax Holiday May 25, 26, 27 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This Memorial Day Weekend, you can buy certain <em>ENERGY STAR</em><sup>®</sup> <em>energy-efficient</em> products <em>tax</em>-free during the annual Texas <em>ENERGY STAR</em> Sales <em>Tax Holiday</em>. There is no limit on the number of qualifying items you can buy, and you do not need to give the seller an exemption certificate to buy items <em>tax</em> free.</p>
<h2>Qualifying Products</h2>
<p>You can buy, rent or lease only the following ENERGY STAR-labeled items tax free:</p>
<ul>
<li>air conditioners (with a sales price of $6,000 or less)</li>
<li>refrigerators (with a sales price of $2,000 or less)</li>
<li>ceiling fans</li>
<li>incandescent and fluorescent light bulbs</li>
<li>clothes washers</li>
<li>dishwashers</li>
<li>dehumidifiers</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_7743" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7743" style="width: 414px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/protect-your-home-from-your-water-heater/tank-style-water-heater-image/" rel="attachment wp-att-7743"><img class="size-full wp-image-7743" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tank-style-water-heater-image.jpg" alt="Waxahachie Plumber Water Heater Duncan Plumbing" width="414" height="537" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tank-style-water-heater-image.jpg 414w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tank-style-water-heater-image-231x300.jpg 231w" sizes="(max-width: 414px) 100vw, 414px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7743" class="wp-caption-text">Water Heater Duncan Plumbing</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Non-Qualifying Products</h2>
<p>Examples of items that do not qualify and are taxable, even if they are ENERGY STAR-labelled include:</p>
<ul>
<li>water heaters</li>
<li>clothes dryers</li>
<li>freezers</li>
<li>stoves</li>
<li>attic fans</li>
<li>heat pumps</li>
<li>wine refrigerators</li>
<li>kegerators</li>
<li>beverage chillers</li>
</ul>
<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions will be on hand to help you install your <em>ENERGY STAR</em><sup>®</sup> <em>energy-efficient appliances for the including dishwashers, clothes washers, clothes dryers and more. </em></p>
<p>Check out the energy star products here:  <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/products/appliances">https://www.energystar.gov/products/appliances</a></p>
<p>More information from the comptroller can be found here: <a href="https://comptroller.texas.gov/taxes/publications/96-1331.php">https://comptroller.texas.gov/taxes/publications/96-1331.php</a></p>
<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions is your hometown, family-owned and operated full service plumbing repair and replacement company. Our appliance service is outstanding.</p>
<div class="column dt-sc-one-third ">
<h4>Awards:</h4>
<ul class="dt-sc-fancy-list arrow">
<li>ELLIS COUNTY PLUMBER OF THE YEAR</li>
<li>2017 PLUMBER OF THE YEAR</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>SOME OF THE BRANDS WE OFFER: </strong></p>
<ul class="dt-sc-fancy-list arrow">
<li>American Standard</li>
<li>Bradford White</li>
<li>Delta</li>
<li>Eljer</li>
<li>GRUNDFOS</li>
<li>Grohe</li>
<li>Kohler</li>
<li>Moen</li>
<li>Price Pfister</li>
<li>Toto</li>
</ul>
<h4>GREEN CERTIFICATIONS:</h4>
<ul class="dt-sc-fancy-list arrow">
<li>gov – Home Performance with energy Star</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="column dt-sc-one-third ">
<h4>DUNCAN PLUMBING AWARDS:</h4>
<ul class="dt-sc-fancy-list arrow">
<li>WAXAHACHIE DAILY LIGHT PLUMBER OF THE YEAR</li>
<li>MIDLOTHIAN MIRROR PLUMBER OF THE YEAR</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="column dt-sc-two-third ">
<blockquote class="type1 "><p>Don’t trust your home or business to just anyone. With Duncan Plumbing Solutions, you have a guarantee on work and service we provide.  Trust the plumbing experts at Duncan Plumbing Solutions to install or repair your plumbing and ensure everything in your home is safe and up to code. Check out some of our reviews!</p></blockquote>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-energy-star-and-water-efficient-products-sales-tax-holiday-may-25-26-27-2019/">Texas Energy Star and Water-Efficient Products Sales Tax Holiday May 25, 26, 27 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-energy-star-and-water-efficient-products-sales-tax-holiday-may-25-26-27-2019/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Does A Tankless Water Heater Work? </title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/how-does-a-tankless-water-heater-work/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/how-does-a-tankless-water-heater-work/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 13:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Appliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company News & Updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gas Lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Green Plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural disasters and plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tankless water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Heaters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adjust water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas or electric water heater Does Not Heat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot water heater inst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot water heater service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instant hot water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[not enough hot water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[not enough hot water from water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tankless water heater install]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7756</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>For maximum performance &#38; energy efficiency, tankless water heaters use on-demand technology. If you don&#8217;t have enough hot water, need more demand hot water or don&#8217;t get enough hot water from your existing tank style water heater, read on to see why millions of consumers have opted for tankless technology. Tankless water heaters ensure safety, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/how-does-a-tankless-water-heater-work/">How Does A Tankless Water Heater Work? </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For maximum performance &amp; energy efficiency, tankless water heaters use on-demand technology. If you don&#8217;t have enough hot water, need more demand hot water or don&#8217;t get enough hot water from your existing tank style water heater, read on to see why millions of consumers have opted for tankless technology. Tankless water heaters ensure safety, save storage space, and cut back on energy costs. Exceedingly popular for many years in Europe and Asia, they are growing in demand in the good &#8216;ole USA for many reasons. Today, standards and certifications like Energy Star run multiple tests on home appliances to ensure fire hazard safety and low maintenance costs. So, what makes a tankless water heater an on-demand technology?</p>
<p>There is no tank. A tankless water heater uses continuous flow to heat water through the device. It does not store heat and re-heat water like the traditional tank-style water heaters. Most traditional and modern units consist of copper heating elements which offer easy thermal conduction. This prevents limescale, mineral, calcium build-up as well. There are all kinds of on-demand models such as hybrid, point-of-use, and combination broilers. But what’s more important than this categorization is knowing which is gas-powered and electric-powered.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7522" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7522" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-7522" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/hotwater_right.jpg" alt="Water Heater Installation" width="600" height="450" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/hotwater_right.jpg 600w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/hotwater_right-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7522" class="wp-caption-text">Water Heater Installation </figcaption></figure>
<p>There are different technologies  depending on the unit that heat water quickly:</p>
<p><b>The Continuous Circulation Method.  </b></p>
<p>This was the first technology used for heating a tankless system. The continuous circulation method constantly pumps water through the water inlet to each corner of the unit. This method is not as energy efficient as newer technologies.  More and more consumers opt for modern, energy-efficient on-demand heating technologies.</p>
<p><b>The Timer Controlled Method. </b></p>
<p>The time controlled method uses a re-circulating pump that shuts off heating the water when the timer goes off. Once the timer is on track, the heating element is activated and cold water is treated. This is one of the most efficient methods and also helps reduce water consumption saving on your water bill as well as your heating gas or electric bill!</p>
<p data-slot-rendered-dynamic="true"><b>The Pump Method. </b></p>
<p data-slot-rendered-dynamic="true">With the pump model, the pump is installed under a sink or in an area where it can be turned on or off with a push of a button. Once it is turned on, the pump uses most of the hot water supply from the unit. This kind of technology is good for when you want single use only. In an RV for example.</p>
<p><b>The Temperature Controlled System. </b></p>
<p>Temperature-controlled models are most common tankless water heaters on the market today. A sensor is placed inside the unit which helps maintain the desired water temperature by activating the burner responsible for running the heating element.  The sensor will turn the pump on and off once the temperature reaches a certain point that is pre-determined.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7744" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7744" style="width: 452px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-7744" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tankless-water-heater-image.jpg" alt="Tankless Water Heater" width="452" height="564" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tankless-water-heater-image.jpg 452w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tankless-water-heater-image-240x300.jpg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 452px) 100vw, 452px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7744" class="wp-caption-text">Tankless Water Heaters Save Space, Energy and Money </figcaption></figure>
<h2>How do they work?</h2>
<p>The best tankless water heater comes with a heating element which continuously heats water and supplies it to your home’s main pipeline. This heating element is also powered by the unit’s power source, which is either electric or gas-powered. When you turn on the tankless water heater, the unit uses gas or electric energy to supply a continuous stream of hot water for as long as the tap is turned on. This means you can run several appliances like a dishwasher, hot water dispenser, run the bath, laundry and take a shower at the same time without running out of hot water. This is one of the biggest benefits for my own family of 5. I wouldn&#8217;t go any other way!</p>
<p>Gas is still preferred over electric-powered heaters because the electric models are slower in delivery than gas-powered units. This is because an electric-powered heater consists of a sensor, a burner and a thermostat. When the switch of the unit is turned on, the sensor that’s placed in the heating element of the electric-powered heater kick-starts the burner. The burner heats the water flowing in the unit in a constant cycle, while the thermostat maintains the desired temperature of the water flow. You typically see units outside the home or in a well ventilated area for the best performance.</p>
<p>Choosing a reputable water heater installation company like Duncan Plumbing Solutions is very important. In addition to working smart, we also take pride in your plumbing aesthetics. We care how our installation looks and want it to be pleasing to the eye! We don’t just install your water heater– Duncan Plumbing Solutions makes your plumbing pretty. We plumb using straight lines with precision right down to the minute details! Duncan Plumbing Solutions will install your water heater with meticulous attention to detail. We take great pride in our work and that shows! It’s the little things that makes Duncan Plumbing Solutions your best choice in water heater installation in Waxahachie, Texas.</p>
<p>You definitely want to choose an experienced company like Duncan Plumbing Solutions when repairing or replacing your water heater. We offer water heaters that will last year after year. We will show you the various options on the market, including the system with the best energy efficiency and lowest running costs, the systems with the best warranties, and the systems that will instantly heat water for your home’s needs.</p>
<h4>Duncan Plumbing Solutions Water Heater Service</h4>
<ul class="dt-sc-fancy-list   arrow">
<li>Water heater inspections, including bringing your existing water heater up to code</li>
<li>Personal delivery of your new water heater; drainage and removal of your old water heater</li>
<li>Connect your new water heater to existing gas, propane or electric and water lines</li>
<li>Fill and test every new &amp; existing water heater</li>
<li>Provide explanation and training for proper use of your tank or tankless water heater</li>
</ul>
<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions is Waxahachie’s trusted plumber when it comes to water heaters! Read some of our reviews here or call us to schedule service!</p>
<figure id="attachment_7519" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7519" style="width: 436px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-7519" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/duncan-dude.png" alt="Best plumber Waxahachie" width="436" height="512" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/duncan-dude.png 436w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/duncan-dude-255x300.png 255w" sizes="(max-width: 436px) 100vw, 436px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7519" class="wp-caption-text">Duncan Plumbing Offers 100% Expert Plumbers</figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/how-does-a-tankless-water-heater-work/">How Does A Tankless Water Heater Work? </a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/how-does-a-tankless-water-heater-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Texas Summers Wreak Havoc on Your Water Lines</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-summers-wreak-havoc-on-your-water-lines/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-summers-wreak-havoc-on-your-water-lines/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 14:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cold Weather Plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leak location and repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outdoor Plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tree roots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Pressure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adjust water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken water main]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busted sewer line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busted water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[causes of a broken water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cedar Hill Plumber 75104]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Desoto Plumber 75115]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ennis Plumber 75119]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fix water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to repair a leak in yard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leak in yard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mansfield Plumber 76063]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sewer smell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water line installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water line repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7749</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Why is there a big increase in water line breaks in the summer (and winter) months? Water lines or water main breaks when the temperatures are extremely hot or extremely cold or when the weather goes from extremely wet to extremely dry. Water lines typically run under the pavement or throughout your yard and are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-summers-wreak-havoc-on-your-water-lines/">Texas Summers Wreak Havoc on Your Water Lines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Why is there a big increase in water line breaks in the summer (and winter) months? Water lines or water main breaks when the temperatures are extremely hot or extremely cold or when the weather goes from extremely wet to extremely dry. Water lines typically run under the pavement or throughout your yard and are the most common system leaks. As you can imagine, the external stress on a pipe increases as the dry frigid air causes the ground above the pipe to freeze and contract just as warm, wet conditions can cause the soil to expand. As soil expands with moist, wet weather followed by extreme dry, arid conditions the stress a used from these normal environmental conditions will causes pressure and compromises to your sewer and water lines.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img class="wp-image-7750" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/70675BE9-6B48-4511-AEB3-7B862CAD508E-907x1024.jpeg" alt="Water lines and sewer lines burst" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/70675BE9-6B48-4511-AEB3-7B862CAD508E-907x1024.jpeg 907w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/70675BE9-6B48-4511-AEB3-7B862CAD508E-266x300.jpeg 266w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/70675BE9-6B48-4511-AEB3-7B862CAD508E-768x867.jpeg 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/70675BE9-6B48-4511-AEB3-7B862CAD508E-600x677.jpeg 600w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/70675BE9-6B48-4511-AEB3-7B862CAD508E.jpeg 1259w" sizes="(max-width: 907px) 100vw, 907px" />
<figcaption>Dry Soil Wreak Havoc on Pipes</figcaption>
</figure>



<p>What are the signs of Broken, Cracked, and Collapsed Pipes and how do you spot the problem before it gets worse?</p>



<p>1.) You Might Smell It! You may notice an odor in your home. With sewer breaks, the stinky smell signifies that the sewage and waste from your house has not been drained into the main public sewer line.</p>



<p>2.) You Might Hear It! Similarly, you may hear bubbling noises whenever you use your sink or flush your toilet. This mostly happens because your pipes have a blockage and the air inside is trying to escape to the sewer system.</p>



<p>3.) You Might See It! Another tale-tell sign that your pipes are cracked, broken or collapsed is that your sewer will start backing up into your home. This is typically caused by obstructions in between the city sewer and your house.</p>



<p>These are the common signs that you might have a problem with your Sewer lines.</p>



<h2>What You Can Do?</h2>



<p>The best thing you can do about a sewer line leak is call a plumber right away. We can use special sewer cameras and video leak detection to figure out what your problem is and fix it fast. The sooner we get there, the sooner we can stop the damage.</p>



<p>What about compromised water lines?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img class="wp-image-7751" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/C8CF0FC8-DCD8-47AE-933A-A953B4B89D51-768x1024.jpeg" alt="Water lines " srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/C8CF0FC8-DCD8-47AE-933A-A953B4B89D51-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/C8CF0FC8-DCD8-47AE-933A-A953B4B89D51-225x300.jpeg 225w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/C8CF0FC8-DCD8-47AE-933A-A953B4B89D51-600x800.jpeg 600w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/C8CF0FC8-DCD8-47AE-933A-A953B4B89D51.jpeg 1050w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" />
<figcaption>Dry Ground Effects Water Lines</figcaption>
</figure>



<p>Just as cold temperatures can cause pipes to freeze and break, dry cracking soil can cause stress on older pipes. Some of the tale-tell signs are:</p>



<p>1.) Wet Spots in the Yard. This is one of the most common ways leaks are detected. If there’s a puddle in your yard or you run your mower through mud, you might have a water line leak.</p>



<p>2.) Lush Green Grass. If you don’t see a puddle or wet area you might see lush green grass. Those patches could be watered by your compromised water lines.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img class="wp-image-7538" src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-1024x983.png" alt="Duncan Plumbing Slutions Waxahachie " srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-1024x983.png 1024w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-300x288.png 300w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-768x737.png 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-600x576.png 600w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck.png 1067w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" />
<figcaption>Call Expert Plumbers Duncan Plumbing Solutions</figcaption>
</figure>



<p>When you suspect a sewer or water line break be sure to call Waxahachie’s hometown plumber Duncan Plumbing Solutions. We are locally owned and family owned and operated. We are plumbers you can trust with the qualifications and equipment. Check our our reviews and you’ll see we are the experienced experts you can trust.<a href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#leak-detection">https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/services/#leak-detection</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-summers-wreak-havoc-on-your-water-lines/">Texas Summers Wreak Havoc on Your Water Lines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/texas-summers-wreak-havoc-on-your-water-lines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protect Your Home From Your Water Heater</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/protect-your-home-from-your-water-heater/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/protect-your-home-from-your-water-heater/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 10:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Water Heaters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas water heater repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumber in red oak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water heater replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waxahachie water heater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waxahachie water heater installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waxahachie water heater repair]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=112</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that your water heater is one of the most common causes of flood damage to your home? What if your water heater busted and leaked all over your home? Is your old tank-style water heater in the attic? That could spell disaster! What can you do to prevent this from happening?   [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/protect-your-home-from-your-water-heater/">Protect Your Home From Your Water Heater</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Water-Heaters-300x188.jpg" alt="Same day service on water heaters " class="wp-image-7737" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Water-Heaters-300x188.jpg 300w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Water-Heaters.jpg 479w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption>DUNCAN PLUMBING OFFERS SAME DAY SERVICE ON TANK AND TANKLESS WATER HEATERS </figcaption></figure>


<h2 style="text-align: center;">Did you know that your water heater is one of the most common causes of flood damage to your home?</h2>
<p style="text-align: left;">What if your water heater busted and leaked all over your home? Is your old tank-style water heater in the attic? That could spell disaster! What can you do to prevent this from happening?  </p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you have the old tank type of water heater, you can place your gas water heater, propane water heater or electric water heater in a water heater pan or water heater drip pan with a drain line piped to the outside, away from your home’s interior and precious belongings.  This is actually common practice. When was the last time you inspected your water heater and pan?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Perhaps you think you&#8217;re safe because you have installed a drain pipe.  A water heater drain pipe is not always a possibility, depending on where the preexisting water heater is located in the house. If you hot water heater is installed in an inaccessible area or if your hot water heater installation didn’t allow for proper drainage this may not be an option. Further, a water heater pan with a drain does not guarantee you are protected from the damages of a leaking water heater.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">A water heater auto shut-off valve offers a solution (or hot water heater shut off valve). Basically the water heater valve ties into the cold water supply line to the water heater, with a sensor located in the water heater pan.  When the sensor detects water, it automatically shuts the cold water supply off to your water heater.Water heater shut off valves offer an affordable and smart way to protect your home from the potential of water damage. Water heater shut-off valves vary in function and price but all are designed to protect your house from flooding from a sudden burst of water from your water heater. The bad news is, sometimes they fail. In this case, you would need to quickly shut off the water to your home in an emergency. Do you know how to do this? A quick lesson in where the main shut off is and how you can access and turn off is something every homeowner should know. Sometimes it&#8217;s as easy as a pair of channel locks. </p>
<p>There are some options to consider when choosing a water heater auto shut-off valve.  Weather you have a gas water heater or electric water heater,  some of the options offer an audible alarm to alert you of a leak.  Some valves not only turn off your water to the water heater but also turn off the power source (i.e. gas or electricity) for gas water heaters or electric water heaters.  Some valves only offer a one-time use—but that one time could save your home! Other water heater shut off valves can be used multiple times.</p>
<p>Some of the most common brands of water heater auto shut-off valves are Wags, Flood Stop, Leak Guardian, and Flood Safe.</p>
<p>Wags: <cite><a href="http://www.taco-hvac.com">www.taco-hvac.com</a></cite></p>
<p><cite></cite>Flood Stop: <a href="http://www.getfloodstop.com">http://www.getfloodstop.com</a></p>
<p>Leak Guardian: <a href="http://www.smarthome.com">http://www.smarthome.com</a></p>
<p>Flood safe: <a href="http://www.watts.com/floodsafe">www.watts.com/floodsafe</a></p>
<p>Prices can vary greatly on the brand and function but installing these products can qualify you for an insurance break which most probably means the shut off valve pays for itself in insurance discounts.</p>
<p>Water heater shut off valves can be easily installed on an existing water heater or on a new installation and offer you peace of mind when you are going with the tank variety of gas or electric water heaters.  Give Duncan Plumbing Solutions call weather you need a plumber in Midlothian, Ennis, Waxahachie, Red Oak or any of surrounding Dallas or Ellis County. We will help you determine which water heater shut off valve is right for you!</p>


<h3 id="tankless-heaters">Tankless Water Heaters</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tankless-water-heater-image.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7744" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tankless-water-heater-image.jpg 452w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tankless-water-heater-image-240x300.jpg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 452px) 100vw, 452px" /></figure>



<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions is your full-service water heater repair, replacement and installation company. We offer residential and commercial tank or space-saving tankless water heaters. From leaks to rusty water, no hot water, erratic temperatures and flow or strange noises from the heater – we have your hot water solution!</p>



<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions is licensed and insured with the State of Texas and can repair or install a new water heater in Waxahachie as well as the entire DFW area. When you need hot water today, call Duncan Plumbing Solutions. We are licensed to repair and install ALL brands of hot water heaters.</p>



<p>We are experts on Tankless water heaters, which provide you with endless hot water and instant hot water while saving space and eliminating worry about a leaking tank system. Tankless water heaters allow you to shower and run major appliances without ever running out of hot water. Instant and endless hot water are just one of the benefits of a tankless water heater by Duncan Plumbing Solutions.</p>



<p>Considering the fuel type is ideal in situations where you are looking to switch water heater systems, such as if you currently own an electric water heater but want to switch to gas instead. Each fuel type has its own set of benefits.</p>



<p><br>Tankless hot water heaters are small and since there is no tank, they are very safe for installing on a 2nd floor. Tankless water heaters are a great option if you don’t have a lot of room or want to install outside of your home. Tankless water heaters are much more efficient and low maintenance vs. the tank models so you can expect to save money in the long run.</p>



<p>Choosing a reputable water heater installation company like Duncan Plumbing Solutions is very important. In addition to working smart, we also take pride in your plumbing aesthetics. We care how our installation looks and want it to be pleasing to the eye! We don’t just install your water heater– Duncan Plumbing Solutions makes your plumbing pretty. We plumb using straight lines with precision right down to the minute details! Duncan Plumbing Solutions will install your water heater with meticulous attention to detail. We take great pride in our work and that shows! It’s the little things that makes Duncan Plumbing Solutions your best choice in water heater installation in Waxahachie, Texas.</p>



<p>You definitely want to choose an experienced company like Duncan Plumbing Solutions when repairing or replacing your water heater. We offer water heaters that will last year after year. We will show you the various options on the market, including the system with the best energy efficiency and lowest running costs, the systems with the best warranties, and the systems that will instantly heat water for your home’s needs.</p>



<h4>Duncan Plumbing Solutions Water Heater Service</h4>



<ul><li>Water heater inspections, including bringing your existing water heater up to code</li><li>Personal delivery of your new water heater; drainage and removal of your old water heater</li><li>Connect your new water heater to existing gas, propane or electric and water lines</li><li>Fill and test every new &amp; existing water heater</li><li>Provide explanation and training for proper use of your tank or tankless water heater</li></ul>



<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions is Waxahachie’s trusted plumber when it comes to water heaters! Read some of our reviews here or call us to schedule service!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tank-style-water-heater-image.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-7743" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tank-style-water-heater-image.jpg 414w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Tank-style-water-heater-image-231x300.jpg 231w" sizes="(max-width: 414px) 100vw, 414px" /></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/protect-your-home-from-your-water-heater/">Protect Your Home From Your Water Heater</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/protect-your-home-from-your-water-heater/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plumbing This Old House</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/plumbing-this-old-house/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/plumbing-this-old-house/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 02:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clogged pipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clogged plumbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clogged toilet repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install pipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new water line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumber Waxahachie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plumbing Repair.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plumbing service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sewer and drain cleaning and repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow drain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow draining toilet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=7731</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Owning a historic home in Waxahachie has its perks; there’s nothing like the character and sturdiness that comes with older homes. But what about that old plumbing? Below are just a few plumbing concerns that come with a historic home: Galvanized pipe Low water pressure Cracked polybutylene pipes Sewer lines Drains Galvanized pipe can be [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/plumbing-this-old-house/">Plumbing This Old House</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Owning a historic home in Waxahachie has its perks; there’s nothing like the character and sturdiness that comes with older homes. But what about that old plumbing?  Below are just a few plumbing concerns that come with a historic home:</p>



<ul><li>Galvanized pipe</li><li>Low water pressure </li><li>Cracked polybutylene pipes</li><li>Sewer lines</li><li>Drains</li><li></li></ul>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/broken-pipe.png" alt="Leak Detection and Slab Leak Repair, Waxahachie, TX" class="wp-image-7440"/><figcaption>GALVANIZED PIPES </figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Galvanized pipe can be the cause of your water pressure pdroblems. The pipes may corrode, causing drops in pressure. Galvanized pipes can also cause water discoloration. </p>



<p>The galvanic process coats the pipes with molten zinc to prevent the iron from corroding. The zinc lasts a time, but not forever. As the zinc erodes, the exposed iron rusts. This can cause pipes to fail, but the warning signal is easy to spot: Your water will become discolored from the rust. </p>



<p>The modern solution is to have galvanized pipes replaced by better and safer alternatives, such as copper or PEX (Cross-Linked Polyethylene). A well-trained plumber can perform this work in relatively short time, ensuring a constant water pressure, no odd taste or color to your water and no leaks.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/pipe-icon.png" alt="Pipe Repair, Waxahachie, TX" class="wp-image-7196"/><figcaption>POLYBUTYLENE PIPES </figcaption></figure></div>



<p></p>



<p>Polybutylene was considered of a good product from the late 70s into the early ’90s because of its low cost and easy installation. It breaks down with exposure to water and water’s dissolved solids, so it is not acceptable anymore. As time goes on, homeowners experience more and more polybutylene pipe problems. My historic home was completely renovated in then 90s using polybutylene pipe and was cracking at every run, every elbow and tee.  An experienced plumber can provide solutions for replacing old PB pipes in your historic home. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/gas-line-icon.png" alt="Gas Line Repair, Waxahachie, TX" class="wp-image-7195"/><figcaption>CLOGGED SEWER LINES </figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Sewer lines are at the top of a lot of people’s historic home plumbing problems. Sewer lines take your home’s black water from drains to the sewer. Sewer lines are always wet, so they attract utree roots. Cast iron pipes are especially susceptible to cracking and being compromised by tree roots, which can clog your sewer lines.</p>



<p>Professional plumbers with the latest equipment will send a camera into your home’s sewer pipe to diagnose, find and fix the roots that clog your sewer lines and clog your plumbing. Sewer cameras show without a doubt the issues, which could be roots or a collapsed sewer line. We will quickly assess the cause of your clogged pipes so the best and most affordable solution can be made for repairing your clogged sewer line. A good plumber will always provide you and your insurance company with the video inspection for peace of mind.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/sink-icon.png" alt="Sink Installation and Repair, Waxahachie, TX" class="wp-image-7175"/><figcaption>DRAINS </figcaption></figure></div>



<p>A clogged or slow drain can quickly escalate into a much bigger problem. Slow drains can indicate the early stages of a clog, pipes that have been narrowed due to mineral or grease buildup, hair, or perhaps something inappropriate has been flushed.  If more than one sink, toilet, or tub at a time becomes clogged in your home, you probably have a clog somewhere in your main drain system rather than in the drains of the individual fixtures. You won’t be able to reach this clog yourself using plungers or chemical drain cleaners. Instead, a professional drain cleaning will be required to reach deep. Another tale-tell sign is water backing up into your tub or multiple areas around your home.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-1024x983.png" alt="" class="wp-image-7538" srcset="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-1024x983.png 1024w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-300x288.png 300w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-768x737.png 768w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck-600x576.png 600w, https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/truck.png 1067w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>DUNCAN PLUMBING SPECIALIZES IN PLUMBING HISTORIC HOMES</figcaption></figure>



<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions can solve all these problems with a quick call. Our professional master plumbers will inspect and solve your older Waxahachie home’s problems, you can rest easy knowing you are in the hands of Waxahachie’s most trusted plumbers. We aren’t your big city franchise that price fixes or trains our guys on how to up sell. We train on how to install, fix and repair your plumbing the good old fashioned way so you can afford to keep that neat historic home!</p>



<p><br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/plumbing-this-old-house/">Plumbing This Old House</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/plumbing-this-old-house/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Old Gas Lines Blamed for Explosions</title>
		<link>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/old-gas-lines-blamed-for-explosions/</link>
				<comments>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/old-gas-lines-blamed-for-explosions/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DuncanPlumbing]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gas Lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cedar Hill Plumber 75104 gas line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Certified Gas Line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Certified gas line replace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ennis Plumber 75119 repair gas lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expert Gas Line Installation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gas Duncanville Plumber 75116]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas line repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas line replacement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas pressure test]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[install gas line Desoto Plumber 75115]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mansfield Plumber 76063 install gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master plumber gas line repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Oak Plumber 75154 install gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[repair gas lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[replace gas lines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas Gas Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas Railroad Commission Certified Gas Line Repair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waxahachie Plumber 75165 install gas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/?p=468</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2013, a plan was unveiled in Austin to remove all natural gas compression couplings and old steel pipes across the state. This means more than half a million homeowners need new gas lines installed or need their corrosive and old gas lines repaired and a gas line pressure test to ensure safety. People have died and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/old-gas-lines-blamed-for-explosions/">Old Gas Lines Blamed for Explosions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2013, a plan was unveiled in Austin to remove all natural gas compression couplings and old steel pipes across the state. This means more than half a million homeowners need new gas lines installed or need their corrosive and old gas lines repaired and a gas line pressure test to ensure safety.</p>
<p>People have died and it’s a serious threat to homeowners across the state of Texas, including communities such as Waxahachie, Red Oak, Cedar Hill, Ennis, Midlothian, Maypearl, Duncanville, DeSoto, Hillsboro and more. Gas leaks can pose a serious safety issue.</p>
<p>For the first time, a commissioner with the state&#8217;s regulating body, Michael Williams, is recommending a statewide fix of the Texas natural gas distribution system, including replacement of the compression couplings.</p>
<p>Replacing all 524,546 steel service lines in Atmos&#8217; Mid-Tex Division, which serves North Texas, could take about 20 years. And because the service line stops at the meter, everything on the home side of the meter remains the customer&#8217;s responsibility. For peace of mind, contact Duncan Plumbing Solutions to ensure your home is safe from corrosive gas lines and a natural gas explosion.</p>
<p>Atmos crews will try to do the work by digging a small hole to the service line, then threading new, bright yellow plastic pipe inside the old line. In the best case, Atmos says, it doesn&#8217;t have to turn off gas service or dig up the yard and the crew leaves the old pipeline in the ground.</p>
<p>In some cases, Atmos must turn off service and dig in the street and yard to remove the old pipeline. Atmos buries its lines 18 inches below ground.</p>
<p>Before turning the gas back on, by law a plumber, such as Duncan Plumbing Solutions must perform a pressure test to ensure the home&#8217;s lines are safe. If the lines inside the home are leaky, it is the homeowners responsibility to repair their gas lines inside the home (on their side of the meter) before the gas can be turned back on.  Make sure your home is safe. Contact Duncan Plumbing Solutions today.</p>
<p>Duncan Plumbing Solutions | Phone: 972-937-0040 | <a href="mailto:info@duncanplumbingsolutions.com">info@duncanplumbingsolutions.com</a> | <a href="http://www.duncanplumbingsolutions.com/">www.duncanplumbingsolutions.com</a> | Expert Gas Line Installation  |  Gas Pressure Test  |  Certified Gas Line  | Texas Gas Line Certified Specialists | Texas Railroad Commission Certified Gas Line Repair  |  Cedar Hill Plumber 75104 | Duncanville Plumber 75116 | Desoto Plumber 75115 | Mansfield Plumber 76063 | Waxahachie Plumber 75165 | Red Oak Plumber 75154 | Waxahachie Plumber 75165 | Ennis Plumber 75119 Master License # M-39624</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/old-gas-lines-blamed-for-explosions/">Old Gas Lines Blamed for Explosions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com">Duncan Plumbing Solutions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://duncanplumbingsolutions.com/old-gas-lines-blamed-for-explosions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
